Guide to the The Inquiry Papers
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Reports and Studies, 1917-1920, undated; Series III
  - Central Africa
    - "The Tsetse Fly in Relation to Sleeping Sickness and Cattle Diseases of Central Africa." By G. M. Wrigley. 6 pp., 1918 January 30 (Box 9A, Folder 107)
  - Central Asia
    - "Central Asia and the Steppe." By R. B. Dixon. 49 pp., 1918 October 14 (Box 9A, Folder 108)
  - Chaco
    See: box 16, folder 244a-244b.
  - Channel Ports
    See:box 12, folder 159-160.
  - Chile
    - "Outline of the Existing Conditions: Chile." [no author] 35 pp., 1918 (Box 9B, Folder 108a)
  - China
    - China [Commerce and Finances]. [no author] 80 pp., Undated (Box 9B, Folder 109)
      Statistical tables.
    - "The Commercial and Financial Activity of the Foreign Powers in China, Considered with Special Reference to Sources of International Discord, (As Between China and the Powers or the Powers Themselves) and with Reference Also to Possible Harmonizing of Those Differences." By A. P. Winston. 7 pp. [precis], Received 1918 August 28 (Box 9B, Folder 110)
    - "The Commercial and Financial Activity of the Powers in China With Special Reference to Sources of International Discord and Possibilities of Harmonizing Those Differences. Report IV. The Financial System of China." By A. P. Winston. 98 pp. [statistical tables], Received 1918 August 27 (Box 9B, Folder 111)
    - "Commercial and Financial Activity of the Powers in China. Report VIII: Foreign Post Offices in China." By A. P. Winston. 21 pp., Received 1918 October 18 (Box 9B, Folder 112)
    - "The Commercial and Financial Activity of the Powers in China, with Special Reference to Sources of International Discord and Possibilities of Harmonizing Those Differences. Report V: Railway Loans to the Chinese Government as Means of Securing a Market for Railway Materials and Equipment." By A. P. Winston. 86 pp. (Box 9B, Folder 113)
    - "Outline for a Government for China." By S. G. Blythe. 10 pp., 1918 March 16 (Box 9B, Folder 114)
    - "The Open Door in Practice (In Regions Other Than Manchuria) to 1914." By S. K. Hornbeck., Undated (Box 9B, Folder 115)
      Excerpted from article for Carnegie Endowment for International Peace.
    - "Open Door Policy in China. Part IV: Russia in North Manchuria to 1914." By S. K. Hornbeck. 43 pp., Undated (Box 9B, Folder 116)
    - [China] [untitled study on population] By A. P. Winston. 83 pp., Undated (Box 9B, Folder 117)
    - "Railways in China. Bibliography." By S. K. Hornbeck. 2 pp., Undated (Box 9B, Folder 118)
    - "Chinese Railways: Review of the General Situation." By F. Lavis. 11 pp., 1918 February (Box 9B, Folder 119)
    - "Railroad Situation in China." By F. C. Hitchcock. 22 pp., 1917 November (Box 9B, Folder 120)
    - "Russian Spheres of Influence in China." [no author] 2 pp. [precis], Undated (Box 9B, Folder 121)
    - "Chinese Treaty Ports and Places Open to Trade in China." By P. T. Moon. 506 pp., 1918 October 23 (Box 9B, Folder 122)
      A descriptive list, with introductory notes and statistical appendices in photostat.
  - Coaling Stations
    - "Coaling Stations and Naval Bases." By P. T. Moon. 14 pp., 1918 nov 4 (Box 10, Folder 123)
      Provisional report. First chapter of final report as outlined in table of contents. Covering letter to Isaiah Bowman. Commentary by A. A. Y[oung].
  - Colombia
    - "Colombia." By O. Hardy. 12 pp., 1918 July 23 (Box 10, Folder 124)
    - "Colombia: Notes on Platinum Industry and Existing Conditions in September, 1918." By W. L. Cook. 4 pp. (Box 10, Folder 125)
      Preliminary study.
    - "Boundary Disputes: The Colombia-Venezuela Boundary." By T. de Booy. 44 pp., Undated (Box 10, Folder 126)
      Maps in photostat.
    - "Outline of the Existing Conditions: Colombia." [no author] 24 pp., 1918 (Box 10, Folder 126a)
    - "Railways in Colombia." [no author] 83 pp., Undated (Box 10, Folder 126b)
  - Colonial Questions
    - "The Colonial Questions." [no author] 88 pp., Undated (Box 10, Folder 127)
      The Pacific Islands; Far East; Inner Asia; Cyprus; Spitzbergen.
    - "Colonial Tariffs and the Open Door." By F. W. Taussig. 5 pp., Received 1918 October 19 (Box 10, Folder 128)
  - Congo
    See: box 8, folder 86.
  - Constantinople and the Straits
    See: box 22-24, folder 326-371.
  - Crimean Peninsula
    - "The Crimean Peninsula with Special Reference to the Crimean Tatars." By R. B. Dixon. 16 pp., 1918 April 10 (Box 10, Folder 129)
  - Cuba
    - "Cuban Sugar versus Sugar from Other Countries in its Relation to the United States." [no author] 2 pp., Undated (Box 10, Folder 129a)
  - Cyprus
    See: box 10, folder 127-128.
    See: box 10, folder 130.
  - Cyprus Convention
    - "The Cyprus Convention of 1878." By Charles Seymour. 5 pp., Received 1918 April 15 (Box 10, Folder 130)
  - Czechs
    See also: box 6-8, folder 43-71.
    See also:box 8, folder 94-96.
    - "A List of Important Documents on the Czecho-Slovak Question (1356-1918)." By Robert J. Kerner. 7 pp., Undated (Box 10, Folder 131)
    - "Memorandum. A Brief Sketch of the Political Movements of the Czecho-Slovaks Tending Toward the Federalization or Dismemberment of Austria-Hungary." By Robert J. Kerner. 43 pp., Received 1918 March 4 (Box 10, Folder 132)
      Includes charts, maps in photostat, statistical tables, oversize sheets.
    - "Czechs in Russia." By M. O. Williams. 4 pp., 1918 August 2 (Box 10, Folder 133)
    - Report of Captain Vladimir S. Hurban of the Czechoslovak Army. 10 pp. [Czechs in Russia], 1918 August 6 (Box 10, Folder 134)
  - Dalmatia
    - "Dalmatia From the Italian Point of View." By H. L. Gray. 167 pp., 1918 July (Box 10, Folder 135)
    - "Ethnographical Notes on Kustenland and Dalmatia." [no author] 13 pp., 1918 (Jun?) (Box 10, Folder 136)
    - "Istria" [and] "Trieste." By T. G. Jackson. 5 pp., Undated (Box 10, Folder 137)
  - Danube
    - "Balkan Peninsula; The Danube and its Internationalization." By W. S. Monroe. 42 pp., 1918 April 10 (Box 10, Folder 138)
      Includes supplemental note, 6 pp..
    - "The Mouths of the Danube with Special Reference to Their Navigability." By L. H. Gray. 7 pp. and statistical tables, 1918 July 24 (Box 10, Folder 139)
  - Danzig
  - Denmark
    See: box 35.
  - Diplomatic History
    - "Diplomatic History. Outline Plan." [no author] 17 pp., 1918 September 1 (Box 11, Folder 140)
  - Don Province
    - "The Don Province." By F. A. Golder. 59 pp., 1918 April 3 (Box 11, Folder 141)
  - Dutch East Indies
    - "The Dutch East Indies." By Clive Day.35 pp., 1918 May 3 (Box 11, Folder 142)
  - East Indies
    See: box 11, folder 142.
  - Eastern Europe
    - "Analysis and Criticism of W. Daya, 'Der Aufmarsch im Osten: Russisch-Asien als Deutsches Kriegs-und Wirtschaftsziel.'" By L. H. Gray. 24 pp., 1918 July 6 (Box 11, Folder 143)
    - "The Political Situation in Eastern Europe." [no author] 5 pp., 1918 December 1 (Box 11, Folder 144)
      Map in photostat.
    - Outline for Work in Eastern Europe: Russia, Lithuania, Finland, Poland, Rumania, Siberia. Notes on Form of Reports. [no author] 21 pp., Undated (Box 11, Folder 145)
    - "Red Book #2. Finland, Hungary. The Boundaries of Rumania." [no author] 14 pp., ndated (Box 11, Folder 146)
    - "Special Report on Western Russia and Poland." By R. H. Lord et al. 71 pp., 1918 November 11 (Box 11, Folder 147)
      Includes Finland, Esthonia, Lettland, Lithuania, Poland, and Ukraine.
  - Economic Penetration
    - "Memorandum - Outline of a Policy for the Control of the 'Economic Penetration' of Backward Countries and of Foreign Investments." By T. B. Veblen. 29 pp., Undated (Box 11, Folder 148)
    - "Economic Penetration." By Walter Lippmann. 6 pp., 1917 December 12 (Box 11, Folder 149)
      Memorandum to Sidney E. Mezes and David Hunter Miller; note in manuscript.
  - Economic Topics
    - "Economic Topics I." By Clive Day. 11 pp., Undated (Box 11, Folder 150)
    - "Economic Desiderata." [no author] 1p., Undated (Box 11, Folder 151)
      List of economic topics to be investigated on Trieste, Fiume, Venice, Bohemia, Moravia, rivers as navigable streams.
  - Ecuador
    - "Outline Study of Existing Conditions: Ecuador." [no author] 25 pp., 1919 (Box 11, Folder 151a)
  - Egypt
    - "Egyptian Problems." By G. L. Beer. 142 pp., 1918 August 9 (Box 11, Folder 152)
  - Educational Reforms
    - "Educational Reforms During the War, Proposed or Accomplished." By P. Monroe, assisted by I. L. Kandel. 44 pp. and 38 pp., Undated (Box 11, Folder 153)
      Includes France, England, Russia, and Germany.
  - Equador
    - "The People of the Valleys of the Piura Tumbes Region." [no author] 6 pp., Undated (Box 11, Folder 154)
      Incomplete.
  - Esthonia
    See: box 8, folder 82-84.
  - Ethnic Groups in the United States
    - Ethnic Groups in the United States: Miscellaneous Interviews. By [Miss] Scudder (for National Research Council). 33 pp., 1918 December 5 (Box 11, Folder 155)
  - Far Eastern Policy
    - "Preliminary Report on Far Eastern Policy." By W. H. Pitkin. 74 pp., 1918 January 12 (Box 11, Folder 156)
  - Finland
    See also: box 4, folder 1.
    See also:box 21, folder 314.
    See also: box 11, folder 143-147.
    See also: box 17-19, folder 252-283.
    - "Finland." By S. E. Morison. 563 pp., 1918 July 24 (Box 11, Folder 157)
  - Foreign Exchange
    - "Control of Foreign Exchange." [no author] 3 pp., Undated (Box 12, Folder 158)
  - France
    See also: box 5-6, folder 18-34.
    - "French North Africa." By G. F. Andrews. 420 pp., Received 1918 July 19 (Box 12, Folder 159)
    - "French Ports on the Channel." By Clive Day. 22 pp., 1918 April 19 (Box 12, Folder 160)
  - Freedom of the Seas
    - "The Freedom of the Seas: The Sinking of the William P. Frye ." By H. S. Oakley. 92 pp. [printed], 1918 January 26 (Box 12, Folder 161)
    - "Tentative Reflections on 'Freedom of the Seas.'" By M. O. Hudson. 5 pp., Undated (Box 12, Folder 162)
  - Galicia
    See:box 6-8, folder 43-71.
  - German Colonies
    See: box 4, folder 5-10.
    See:box 12, folder 163-170.
  - Germany
    See also: box 4, folder 5-10.
    - "First Red Book: Proposed New Boundaries for Germany." [no author] 15 pp., Undated (Box 12, Folder 163)
    - Projects of Studies: German Commerce, Commercial Policy, and Other Projects." By Clive Day. 1 p., 1918 April 23 (Box 12, Folder 164)
    - "Information on Economic Matters From the German Press." By V. Clark (?) 8 pp., Undated (Box 12, Folder 165)
    - "Some, but not all, of von Kuehlmann's assertions and their interpretation in the light of earlier German and Austrian statements." By P. T. Moon. 14 pp., 1918 June 24 (Box 12, Folder 166)
    - "The Pacific Colonies of Germany." By W. Churchill [Sometime Consul-General of the United States for Samoa]. 251 pp., 1918 December (Box 12, Folder 167)
    - "General Summary on Former German Pacific Island Possessions." By G. H. Blakeslee., Undated (Box 12, Folder 168)
      Supplementary to Report "Marshall, Caroline, and Mariana Islands in Relation to Japan and the United States." Nov. 18, 1918. 88 pp.
    - "Possible Territorial Changes in the German Empire." [no author] 12 pp., Undated (Box 12, Folder 169)
      Note in manuscript: "to General Bliss - December 24".
    - "Political Organization of Germany." By M. Smith. 3 pp. [abstract], Received 1918 November 15 (Box 12, Folder 170)
  - Gibraltar
    - "A Brief Sketch of Gibraltar and its Occupation by Great Britain." [no author] 25 pp., Undated (Box 12, Folder 171)
  - Great Britain
    - "The Effect of the War Upon the Commercial Policy of Great Britain." By G. P. Fuller. 33 pp., Received 1918 June 18 (Box 12, Folder 172)
    - "A Brief Syllabus of Foreign Relations of Great Britain, 1870-1914." By E. F. Davison. 20 oversize pp., Undated (Box 13, Folder 173)
  - Guatemala
    - Handwritten notes on Zur Geographie der Republik Guatemala. [no author] 6 pp., Undated (Box 13, Folder 173a)
  - Hague Conferences
    - "The Hague Conferences." [no author] 8 pp., Undated (Box 13, Folder 174)
  - Haiti
    - "Haiti and Coffee." [no author] 10 pp., Undated (Box 13, Folder 174a)
  - Holland
    See also: box 11, folder 142.
    - [Holland: Summary of laws regulating education.] [no author] 24 pp., Undated (Box 13, Folder 175)
  - Hungary
    See: box 11, folder 143-147.
  - Immigration
    - "Immigration As An International Economic Problem." By S. Joseph. 3 pp., 1918 February 18 (Box 13, Folder 176)
  - India
    - "India: Agriculture and Allied Industries." By D. Kenyon. 70 pp., Received 1918 June 3 (Box 13, Folder 177)
      Pages 10, 12, 27-31, 65 missing.
    - "British Education in India." [no author] 60 pp., Undated (Box 13, Folder 178)
      Digest 17 pp.; title page and p. i of Table of Contents missing.
    - "India, Economics: Famines in India." By D. Kenyon. 46 pp., Received 1918 June 3 (Box 13, Folder 179)
    - "India Government: Certain Aspects of Finance." By D. Kenyon. 88 pp. (incomplete), Received 1918 June 3 (Box 13, Folder 180)
    - "History of India." By D. Kenyon. 40 pp., Received 1918 June 3 (Box 13, Folder 181)
      Includes Afghanistan, Burma and Tibet; pp. 40-50A missing,
    - "India Economics: Industries." By D. Kenyon. 2 parts, 47 pp. and 57 pp., Received 1918 June 3 (Box 13, Folder 182)
      Charts pp. 9, 10, 15, 23, 26 (second section) and Key to money of India (at end) missing.
    - "India Economics: Irrigation." By D. Kenyon. 47 pp., Received 1918 June 3 (Box 13, Folder 183)
      [Key to money of India missing.
    - "India Economics: Milling and Mineral Resources." By D. Kenyon. 69 pp., Received 1918 June 3 (Box 13, Folder 184)
      Pages 5A, 29A (2 parts), 42A (2 parts), 45A, 57A (2 parts) and Key to money of India missing.
    - "India Government: Political Structure and Activities, Part I, Political Structure." By D. Kenyon (?). 210 pp., Received 1918 June 3 (Box 13, Folder 185)
    - "India Economics: Railways." By D. Kenyon. 90 pp., received 1918 June 3 (Box 13, Folder 186)
      Page iv (Table of Contents), Tables (6A, 8A and 8B, 54A), Appendix III, Key to money of India missing.
    - "Certain Outstanding Features of Recent Indian Reform Movement with Special Reference to Extent of Moslem Participation Therein." [no author] 3 pp., Undated (Box 14, Folder 187)
    - "Memorandum on Some Aspects of Social, Religious, and Political Conditions in India." By C. Bonner. 62 pp., 1918 March 20 (Box 14, Folder 188)
    - "India Economics: Trade and Commerce." By D. Kenyon. 82 pp., Received 1918 June 3 (Box 14, Folder 189)
      Charts p. 5A-B, 34A, 38A, 61A, and Key to money of India missing.
  - Inner Asia
  - International Court
    - "An International Court." [no author] 4 pp., Undated (Box 14, Folder 190)
      Includes note in manuscript,
  - International Currency
    - "Suggestions Relating to International Currency." By D. E. Smith. 10 pp., 1918 April (Box 14, Folder 191)
  - International Law
    - "International Law: A Summary." [no author] 20 pp., Undated (Box 14, Folder 192)
    - "The American Program and International Law." By Walter Lippmann. 133 pp., 1917 December 28 (Box 14, Folder 193)
      Includes covering letter to Colonel House.
  - International Tariff Court
    - Critique of A. A. Young's Memorandum, "Possible International Action with Respect to Tariffs." By David Hunter Miller. 8 pp., 1918 January 12 (Box 14, Folder 194)
      To Sidney E. Mezes.
  - Islamism
    See: box 16, folder 232.
    See: box 6, folder 35.
  - Istrian Islands
    See: box 24, folder 380.
  - Italy
    See also:box 6-8, folder 43-71.
    See also:box 10, folder 135-137.
    See also:box 11, folder 150-151.
    See also: box 22-24, folder 326-371.
    - "The Government of Italy." By W. T. Morgan. 14 pp., Received 1918 January 30 (Box 14, Folder 195)
    - "Political Parties in Italy." By W. T. Morgan. 10 pp., Received 1918 January 30 (Box 14, Folder 196)
    - "Italian Tyrol." By W. E. Lunt. 200 pp., 1918 November 13 (Box 14, Folder 197)
    - "Memorandum for the President: Suggested boundary between the Italians and the Jugo-Slavs." [no author] 6 pp., 1918 December 18 (Box 14, Folder 198)
    - "The Italian Secret Treaty and the Principle of Nationality." [no author] 5 pp., Undated (Box 14, Folder 199)
  - Japan
    - "Digest of Dr. Abbott's Report." By W. H. Pitkin. 8 pp., 1918 February 17 (Box 14, Folder 200)
    - "Economic Activity of Japan in China." By A. P. Winston. 120 pp., Undated (Box 14, Folder 201)
    - "Japan: Education." By P. Monroe (?). 58 pp., Undated (Box 14, Folder 202)
    - "Japanese Immigration into the United States." By W. Pitkin. 25 pp., Undated (Box 14, Folder 203)
      Recommendations as to the handling of this problem.
    - "Japanese Spheres of Influence in China." By W. H. Pitkin. 22 pp., Undated (Box 14, Folder 204)
    - "Preliminary Report on Population and Industrial Development of Japan." By J. F. Abbott. 13 pp., 1918 January 25 (Box 14, Folder 205)
  - Kurds
  - Kustenland
    See: box 10, folder 135-137.
  - Latin America
    - "Some of the Data Needed for South America." [no author]., Undated (Box 14, Folder 206)
    - "Memorandum from C. E. McGuire concerning Latin America and the Peace Conference from the point of view of the United States." 5 pp., 1918 April (Box 14, Folder 206a)
    - "Comments on Memorandum Submitted by C. E. McGuire in Reference to Latin America and the Peace Conference." By H. Bruere. 3 pp., 1918 April (Box 14, Folder 207)
    - Miscellaneous reports on Latin America. By B. Willis. (Box 14, Folder 208)
      Includes covering memorandum from B. Willis to Isaiah Bowman, 1918 Dec 3.
    - Latin America: Summaries of political, economic, and historical information. [no author], Undated (Box 15, Folder 209)
      Oversize.
    - "Summary of Current Strategic Situation in Latin America." [no author] 20 pp., Undated (Box 15, Folder 209a)
    - "Ecclesiastical Jurisictions in Latin America." [no author] 80 pp., Undated (Box 15, Folder 209b)
    - "Population of the American Republics, according to the latest data in the Pan American Union." [no author] 3 pp., 1918 July 19 (Box 15, Folder 209c)
    - "Criticism of Professor McDonald's Report on Latin America and a possible Peace Conference." By Manley O. Hopkins. 1 p., 1918 February 9 (Box 15, Folder 209c)
    - "Zone of areism (no appreciable surface run-off) in South America." [no author] 2 pp., Undated (Box 15, Folder 209c)
  - Latvia [and United Esthonia]
  - Law of the Air
    - "Law of the Air, Bibliographical Memorandum." By David Hunter Miller. 4 pp., 1918 March 12 (Box 15, Folder 210)
  - League of Nations
    - "President Lowell's draft of a Convention for the League of Nations." 17 pp., Received 1918 March 12 (Box 15, Folder 211)
      Revised edition.
  - Lebanon
  - Lettland
    - "The Lettish Question." By Sidney B. Fay. 66 pp., 1918 March 12 (Box 15, Folder 212)
  - Lithuania
    - "Lithuania." By F. A. Golder. 42 pp., Undated (Box 15, Folder 213)
    - "Lithuania." By F. A. Golder. 88 pp., 1918 March 12 (Box 15, Folder 214)
    - "Lithuania." By F. A. Golder. 156 pp., 1918 August 20 (Box 15, Folder 215)
    - "Reorganized Report of Report by Mr. Golder on Lithuania." By F. R. Flournoy. 32 pp., Received 1918 February 27 (Box 15, Folder 216)
    - "Report on Conditions and Events in Lithuania Since the Beginning of the War." [no author] 218 pp. [bound], Undated (Box 15, Folder 217)
    - "Brief on the Independence of Lithuania." By J. Szlupas. 10 pp., Received 1918 August 22 (Box 15, Folder 218)
    - "Lithuania: Lithuanian Political Parties in America." By F. A. Golder. 7 pp., 1918 April 12 (Box 15, Folder 219)
  - Luxemburg
    - "Luxemburg." By L. D. Steefel. 109 pp., 1918 April 10 (Box 15, Folder 220)
  - Macedonia
    - "Macedonia." By A. C. Coolidge. 11 pp., 1918 October 29 (Box 15, Folder 221)
    - "Sources for Macedonian and Albanian Boundaries." By W. S. Monroe. 5 pp., 1918 May 22 (Box 15, Folder 222)
    - "The Case for a Free Macedonia." By A. Sonnichsen. 27 pp., Received 1918 January 28 (Box 15, Folder 223)
    - Nationalist Schools in Macedonia By W. S. Monroe. 13 pp., Received 1918 June 14 (Box 15, Folder 224)
      Includes Greek, Bulgarian, Serbian, and Rumanian.
  - Maritime Law
    - Maritime Law. Memorandum. [no author] 5 pp., Undated (Box 15, Folder 225)
  - Mediterranean
    - "The Mediterranean Basin - The Heart of the War." By Frederic C. Howe. 7 pp., 1918 Feb27 (Box 16, Folder 225a)
  - Merchant Marine
    - Merchant Marine. Miscellaneous memoranda. By M. G. Marsh (?). 29 pp., Received 1918 January 28 (Box 16, Folder 226)
  - Mesopotamia
    - "Mesopotamia." By D. C. Munro. 18 pp., 1918 January 31 (Box 16, Folder 227)
    - "Report on Mesopotamia." By E. C. Semple. 57 pp., 1918 February 1 (Box 16, Folder 228)
      Includes Supplementary Note on the General Strategic Position of Mesopotamia. By D. W. Johnson. Undated. 5 pp.
  - Mexico
    - "Preliminary Report on the Petroleum in Mexico." By E. W. Shaw. 13 pp., 1918 June 26 (Box 16, Folder 228a)
  - Middle Africa
    - "Middle Africa: Problems of International Cooperation and Control." By G. L. Beer. 104 pp., 1918 October 31 (Box 16, Folder 229)
  - Mineral Deposits
    - "Mineral Deposits of the World. Part I: Distribution of Deposits and Production by Mining Districts." [Department of the Interior: United States Geological Survey.] 109 pp., 1918 July (Box 16, Folder 230)
  - Mineral Production
    - "Mineral Production of the World for 1913." [Department of the Interior: United States Geological Survey.] 109 pp., 1918 January 22 (Box 16, Folder 231)
      Maps missing.
  - Mohammedan World
    - "The Mohammedan World." By L. Dominian. 76 pp., 1918 May 20 (Box 16, Folder 232)
  - Monroe Doctrine
    - "The Monroe Doctrine, a Brief Report." By W. E. Dodd. 24 pp., 1918 February 2 (Box 16, Folder 233)
    - "The Present Status of the Monroe Doctrine." By W. E. Dodd. 13 pp., Undated (Box 16, Folder 234)
  - Mozambique
    - "Economic Conditions in Mozambique and Annual Report for 1917." By John F. Jewell [Consul, Lourenco Marques, Portugese East Africa]. 38 pp., 1918 June 20 (Box 16, Folder 235)
  - Nationalism
    - "Nationalism, Individualization of Function and the Creation of Values." By W. I. Thomas. 5 pp., Undated (Box 16, Folder 236)
  - Near Eastern Question
    - "The German and Austrian Solutions of the Near Eastern Question (A Hasty Survey)." By Robert J. Kerner. 20 pp., 1918 March 4 (Box 16, Folder 237)
  - New Zealand
    - "Notes on Remarks Made by Premier Massey and Finance Minister Ward of New Zealand on the Attitude of the Dominion Government to the After War Settlement." By P. Slosson. 11 pp., 1918 sep 11 (Box 16, Folder 238)
  - Nigeria
    - "Notes on the Topography of Nigeria." By Mrs. Robert W. Jones. 14 pp., Undated (Box 16, Folder 239)
  - North Africa
    See: box 12, folder 159.
  - Open Door
    See: box 9B, folder 109-122.
    See: box 10, folder 128.
  - Opium Problem
    - "Diplomatic Aspects of the Opium Problem (1906-1918)." By W. R. Smith. 31 pp., Undated (Box 16, Folder 240)
  - Ottoman Empire
  - Pacific Islands
    See:box 10, folder 127-128.
    See: box 12, folder 167.
    See: box 12, folder 168.
  - Palestine
    - "Palestine." [no author] 58 pp., Undated (Box 16, Folder 241)
    - "Palestine and Jewish Nationalism." [no author] 9 pp., Undated (Box 16, Folder 242)
  - Pan-Germanism
    - "Literature of Pan-Germanism." By T. G. Masaryk. 19 pp., 1918 July (Box 16, Folder 243)
      Bibliographical study.
  - Pan-Turanian Movement
    - "Pan-Turanian Movement." [no author] 14 pp., Undated (Box 16, Folder 244)
  - Paraguay
    - "Outline Study of Existing Conditions: Paraguay." [no author] 25 pp., 1919 (Box 16, Folder 244a)
    - "Criticism of the map of Paraguay made by R. Mayer." [no author] 5 pp., 1918 August 7 (Box 16, Folder 244b)
  - Paraguay, the Chaco